Partial Register of the Ronald MacArthur Hirst papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Normandy Operations Files, 1963-2004 (Box 64-99)
  - Subject files (including Normandy treks) (Folder 79)
    - Military units, 1983-2004 (Folder 83)
      - 404th Fighter Group, 1992-1994 (Folder 84)
      - 405th Fighter Group, 1988-1998 (Folder 84)
      - 406th Fighter Group, 1994 (Folder 84)
      - 474th Fighter Group, 1993-1994 (Folder 84)
      - 555th Signal Air Warning Battalion, 1997-2004 (Folder 84)
      - 563rd Signal Air Warning Battalion, 1993-2004 (Folder 84)
      - 573rd Signal Air Warning Battalion, 1997-2003 (Folder 85)
      - 723rd Railway Operating Battalion, 1997-2000 (Folder 85)
      - 922nd Engineer Aviation Regiment, 1989-2004 (Folder 85)
      - 942nd Engineer Aviation Topographic Battalion, 1997-1998 (Folder 85)
      - Communications Zone, 1997-2001 (Folder 85)
      - Headquarters, Provisional Engineer Special Brigade Group, 1998-2000 (Folder 85)
    - Mulberry (artificial) harbors, 2003-2004 (Folder 85)
    - Museums, 1984-2004 (Folder 85)
      - Air Force (proposed), 1984-1992 (Folder 85)
      - Caen Memorial Museum, 1987-2004 (Folder 85)
      - Pierre Claeyssens Military Museum (proposed), Santa Barbara, CA, 2003 (Folder 86)
    - National Archives and Records Administration (U.S.), 1984-2004 (Folder 86)
    - National Guard, 1994-2004 (Folder 86)
    - Navy, undated (Folder 86)
    - Newspapers, Normandy, 1983-1994 (Folder 86)
    - Night Fighters (P-61 pilots), 1983-2004 (Folder 86)
    - Ninth Air Force, 1974-2003 (Folder 86)
      - General, (2 folders) (Folder 86)
      - Air Defense Command, 1987-2003 (Folder 87)
      - Bomber Command, 1984-1995 (Folder 87)
      - Engineer Command, 1984-2003 (Folder 87)
      - Fighter Command, 1983-1993 (Folder 87)
      - Service Command, 1986-2003 (Folder 87)
      - Tactical Air Command, 1974-1997 (Folder 87)
      - Troop Carrier Command, 1983-2003 (Folder 87)
    - Norman chateaux, 1995 (Folder 87)
    - Normandy Allies, Inc., 1999-2001 (Folder 87)
    - Normandy American Cemetery, 2002-2004 (Folder 88)
    - Normandy Band (Great Britain), 2003 (Folder 88)
    - Normandy Treks (tours guided by Hirst), 1969-2004 (Folder 88)
      - 1969 (Folder 88)
      - 1983 (Folder 88)
      - 1984 (Folder 88)
      - 1989 (Folder 88)
      - 1992 (Folder 88)
      - 1993 (Folder 88)
      - 1994, (2 folders) (Folder 88)
      - 1995 (Folder 88)
      - 1996 (Folder 89)
      - 1997 (Folder 89)
      - 1998 (Folder 89)
      - 2000 (Folder 89)
      - 2001 (Folder 89)
      - 2002 (Folder 89)
      - 2003 (Folder 89)
      - 2004 (Folder 89)
    - Nurses, 1988-2004 (Folder 89)
    - Omaha Beach, 1999-2002 (Folder 90)
    - Peregory, Frank, 2000 (Folder 90)
    - "Return to England" reunion, 1992 (Folder 90)
    - Rocci, Thomas (memorial for), 2002 (Folder 90)
    - Royal Air Force, 1994 (Folder 90)
    - Royal Air Force Advanced Landing Groups, 1993-2004 (Folder 90)
    - Schools, Normandy, 1994 (Folder 90)
    - SHAEF, 1998-2004 (Folder 90)
    - Southern Tourist Board (Great Britain), 1994 (Folder 90)
    - Stars and Stripes coverage of anniversaries, 1989-1994 (Folder 90)
    - Television coverage of 50th anniversary, 1994 (Folder 90)
    - Utah Beach, 1993-2004 (Folder 90)
    - V Corps Veterans/Memorial, 1989-1997 (Folder 90)
    - VII Corps command post (Yvetot-Bocage), 1996-1997 (Folder 90)
    - Vouilly (chateau), 1995-1996 (Folder 90)
    - Wall of Liberty (Utah Beach), 1999-2004 (Folder 90)
    - Weather, 1993-1994 (Folder 90)
  - Veterans associations/Veterans memoirs (Folder 91)
    - Associations (Folder 91)
      - American Fighter Aces Association (Folder 91)
        - General, 1996-2000 (Folder 91)
        - Trip to Germany, 1999 (Folder 91)
      - Buddies of the Ninth Association (BOTNA), 1991-2004 (Folder 91)
      - 9th Air Force Association (Folder 91)
        - Correspondence, 1996-2004 (Folder 91)
        - General, 1990-1994 (Folder 91)
        - General, 1995-2004 (Folder 91)
        - Cruise, 1994 (Folder 91)
        - Memorial, 1989-1995 (Folder 91)
        - Reunion in Normandy, 1990 (Folder 92)
        - V-E Day tour, 1995 (Folder 92)
      - P-38 National Association, 1984-2002 (Folder 92)
      - P-47 Thunderbolt Pilots Association, 1983-2004 (Folder 92)
      - P-51 Mustang Pilots Association, 1983-2004 (Folder 92)
      - RECCE (Tactical Reconnaissance Group veterans), 1983-2003 (Folder 92)
    - Memoirs and unit histories (Folder 92)
      - Adventures by Men of the 60th Infantry Regiment, the Ninth Infantry Division, 1993 (Folder 92)
      - The American Assault Exercises at Slapton Sands, Devon, in 1944, by Arthur Clamp, undated (Folder 92)
      - A Brief History of the 323rd Bomb Group (Medium), August 1942 - December 1945, by Eric Smith, 1987 (Folder 92)
      - A Brief History of the 395th Signal Company Aviation, compiled by Fay Hart, undated (Folder 92)
      - Consolidated Lists of All Sites of the Signal Air Warning Battalions, 6 June 1944 - 7 May 1945, edited by Col. Maurice E. Byrne, 1997 (Folder 92)
      - Freight Moves Faster by Air, 31st Transport Group, 1996 (Folder 93)
      - History of the 510th Fighter Squadron, 405th Fighter Group, for the month of June 1944, by James L. Gleeson (Folder 93)
      - History of 555th Signal Aircraft Warning Battalion, undated (Folder 93)
      - History of the 942nd Engineer Aviation Topographic Battalion, April 4, 1944 - November 20, 1945, compiled by Robert des Granges, 1989 (Folder 93)
      - Little Known Facts of a Well Known War, by Q.R. Walsh, 1994 (Folder 93)
      - Memoirs of the 830th Engineer Aviation Battalion, by Morck Hancock, 1973 (Folder 93)
      - Minnesota Farm Boy Goes to War (IX Tactical Air Command), by Orville B. Iverson, 1996 (Folder 93)
      - Mission Accomplished: A Brief Narrative of the 552nd Anti-Aircraft Artillery Automatic Weapons Battalion, undated (Folder 93)
      - Music and Morale, Memories of E.T.O. Days, Chansoneers, 50th anniversary edition, by William E. Beatty, 1996 (Folder 93)
      - The Ninth Infantry Division in WWII, as Told by Its Men, vol. II, undated (Folder 94)
      - Nothing Is Constant Except Change: A Factual Summary of Organizational Activities of the 573rd Signal Aircraft Warning Battalion, 1945 (Folder 94)
      - Plowing Through Life, by Sherl Edward Hasler, 2003 (Folder 94)
      - Our Finest Hours, 862nd Engineer Aviation Battalion, 2001 (Folder 94)
      - Semi-Official History of the 926 Signal Battalion, compiled by Raymond Mattson, 1970 (Folder 94)
      - Spotlight: A History of the 563rd Signal Air Warning Battalion in Combat in World War II, 1993 (Folder 94)
      - 336th Engineer Combat Battalion (reunion program), 1994 (Folder 94)
      - Transport Wing 302, undated (Folder 94)
      - Unit History, Detachment "A," 942 Engineer Aviation Topographic Bn., prepared by Lewis Phillips and William Mountz, 1944 (Folder 94)
      - World War II, D-Day Landing Normandy, France and Beyond! (copied from diary of Lt. Joseph Burby), 1994 (Folder 94)
    - Newsletters (Folder 94)
      - American Fighter Aces and Friends Bulletin, 1997-1998 (Folder 94)
      - BOTNA Bulletin (Buddies of the 9th Association) (Folder 94)
        - 1989-1998 (Folder 94)
        - 1999-2004 (Folder 95)
      - Flight Patterns (369th fighter Squadron Association), 1983 (Folder 95)
      - 474th Fighter Group Association, 1984-2003 (Folder 95)
      - 493rd Word (493rd Fighter Squadron Association), 1983-2003 (Folder 95)
      - JUG Letter (P-47 Thunderbolt Pilots), 1983-2004 (Folder 95)
      - Liaison Spoken Here (International Liaison Pilot and Aircraft Association), 1997-2003 (Folder 95)
      - Lightning Strikes (P-38 National Association), 1992-2004 (Folder 95)
      - Milk Run (344th Bomb Group Association), 1998-2002 (Folder 95)
      - Newsletter, 453rd Bomb Squadron Association, 1988-1993 (Folder 96)
      - The Ninth Flyer (9th Air Force Association) (Folder 96)
        - 1991-1994 (Folder 96)
        - 1995-1998 (Folder 96)
        - 1999-2001 (Folder 96)
        - 2002-2004 (Folder 96)
      - P-51 Mustang Pilots Assn. (Folder 96)
        - 1983-1993 (Folder 96)
        - 1994-2004 (Folder 97)
      - Poop Sheet, 404th Fighter Group, 1995-2002 (Folder 97)
      - The Sawbuck Gazette (veterans of Signal Air Warning Battalions), 1999-2004 (Folder 97)
      - The SHAEF Communiqué (SHAEF Veterans Association) (Folder 97)
        - 1995-1998 (Folder 97)
        - 1999-2004 (Folder 97)
      - 604th Squadron Association Newsletter (Folder 97)
        - 1991-1995 (Folder 97)
        - 1996-2000 (Folder 98)
        - 2001-2004 (Folder 98)
      - Starduster (406th Fighter Group Memorial Association), 1989-2004 (Folder 98)
      - Yea Botz (557th Bomb Squadron Association), 1987-1995 (Folder 98)
    - Miscellaneous research material (Folder 98)
      - Aerodrome de Cherbourg-Maupertus, circa 1981 (Folder 98)
      - D-Day: Forty Years plus One, by Albert H. Smith, Jr. (reprint from Infantry, May-June 1985) (Folder 98)
      - Down Ramp! The Story of the Army Amphibian Engineers (excerpt), by William F. Heavey (Folder 98)
      - Effect of Air Power on Military Operations, Western Europe, by Gen. Omar Bradley, circa 1944 (Folder 98)
      - 50th Anniversary of World War II Commemoration Committee (Arlington, VA), assorted materials (Folder 98)
      - G-2 Section, parts V-VII, 12th Army Group, Report of Operations, circa 1945 (Folder 99)
      - Headquarters, 12th Army Group (Final After Action Report), circa 1945 (Folder 99)
      - History, Headquarters, IX Air Defense Command (copy from National Archives) (Folder 99)
      - Holding the Line: The 51st Engineer Combat Battalion and the Battle of the Bulge, by Ken Hechler, 1988 (Folder 99)
      - Omaha, by Raymond Couraud, Ronald Hirlé, Sandrine Woelffel, and others (galley proof), 2004 (Folder 99)
      - Operation Overlord in English, by Philippe Jutras, undated (Folder 99)
      - Radar in ETO Air-Ground Operations, by E. Blair Garland (typed copy) (Folder 99)
- Other Research Projects, 1967-2004 (Box 100-106)
  Correspondence, manuscript draft, magazine and newspaper clippings, arranged alphabetically by subject or correspondent.
  - Correspondence, general (Folder 99)
    - Bahr, Gerhard, 1987 (Folder 99)
    - Benkel, Uwe, 1992-1999 (Folder 99)
    - Besson, Jacques, 1995-2002 (Folder 99)
    - Carisella, Pat (research about Manfred von Richthofen), 1997 (Folder 99)
    - Cassagneres, Ev, 1991-1997 (Folder 99)
    - Faber, Manfred, 1993 (Folder 99)
    - Gesellschaft für Wehr- und Sicherheitspolitik (Wiesbaden), 1990-1997 (Folder 99)
    - Heine, Friedrich, 1976-1999 (Folder 99)
    - Hugel, Max, 1983 (Folder 100)
    - Nitsch, Wolfgang, 1995-2003 (Folder 100)
    - Robinson, Plater, 1978-1995 (Folder 100)
    - Royal Military Academy, Sandhurst, 1993-2001 (Folder 100)
    - Siemon, Bruce, U.S. Army Europe, Office of Military History, 1977-2003 (Folder 100)
    - Smithsonian National Air and Space Museum, 1983-1998 (Folder 100)
    - Stars and Stripes (newspaper) (Folder 100)
      - 50th anniversary commemoration, 1992 (Folder 100)
      - 1978-1988 (Folder 100)
      - 1989-1993 (Folder 100)
      - 1994-2004 (Folder 100)
      - Stars and Stripes Association News, 1993-1994 (Folder 100)
    - United States Air Force, 1967-1974 (Folder 100)
  - Subjects, general (Folder 101)
    - Association of Former Intelligence Officers, 1990-1996 (Folder 101)
    - Barth, Germany (site of STALAG-Luft I), 2001-2003 (Folder 101)
    - Durnbach (burial site for American airmen killed in Germany), (3 folders) (Folder 101)
    - Fliegerhorst Airfield Kaserne, Hanau (proposed excavation), 1987 (Folder 101)
    - Lindbergh, Charles, 1997-2002; (2 folders) (Folder 101)
    - Lindsey Air Base, Wiesbaden, Germany (Folder 102)
      - "Ninety Years at Lindsey, or How to Gold Plate an Antique," by Ronald M.A. Hirst, 1987 (Folder 102)
        - Part I (Folder 102)
        - Part II (Folder 102)
        - Part III (Folder 102)
      - Research material, (2 folders) (Folder 103)
      - Luftwaffe (German), 1986-2001 (Folder 103)
    - Ninth Infantry Division veterans (Folder 103)
      - 1970-1993 (Folder 103)
      - 1994-1999 (Folder 104)
      - 2000-2004 (Folder 104)
      - Newsletter, "The Octofoil" (Folder 104)
        - 1980-1987 (Folder 104)
        - 1988-1997 (Folder 104)
        - 1998-2004 (Folder 104)
    - Remagen - Ludendorff Bridge (Folder 105)
      - Correspondence, general, 1978-2002; (4 folders) (Folder 105)
      - Research material (Folder 105)
      - Research material, (continued, 2 folders) (Folder 106)
      - Reunions and commemorations (Folder 106)
        - 1995 (Folder 106)
        - 2000 (Folder 106)
        - 2002 (Folder 106)
      - Schmidt-Carell, Paul, 1988-1989 (Folder 106)
      - Westmoreland, Gen. William, 1982-1983 (Folder 106)
    - Warbington, Louis (CARE packages), 1996-1998 (Folder 106)
    - Wohlsborn (site of U.S. Army Air Force crash, 1944), 2001 (Folder 106)
- Oversize Materials (Box 107-108)
  Includes posters, maps, architectural drawings, and large photographs about the Normandy landing, Lindsey Air Base, the Berlin Airlift, and the Battle of Stalingrad.
- Incremental Materials (Box 109-188)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described.
  - Declassified U.S. government records, 1944 (Box 141)
    Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
    - 2015 May release of records, 1944
      Photocopies of descriptions, maps, and call signs of Allied airfields on the Continent.